Alexandros Efstratiou

Profile

Social psychologist and behavioral scientist with interests in intergroup processes and decision-making. I apply these concepts to studying misinformation (and general information processing) and polarization online in the interdisciplinary field of computational social science.

Core skills and competencies

- Frequentist statistical analysis
- Experimental and survey design
- Behavioral intervention design
- Expertise in intergroup theory
- Expertise in dual-process theories of decision-making & risk perception
- Critical analysis of performance metrics

Education

PhD in Cybersecurity

University College London (UCL), London, UK

Supervisors: Prof. Emiliano De Cristofaro, Dr Tristan Caulfield

My research looks at intergroup interaction/polarization dynamics and how they affect the spread of misinformation.

MSc in Behavioural Science (Distinction - 79.2)

Durham University, Durham, UK

Key skills developed: Behavioral intervention design, intervention evaluation, decision-making theory, cognition of information processing

BSc in Psychology (First Class Honours – 78.85, GPA 4.25)

University of East Anglia, Norwich, UK

Sep 2016 - June 2019

July 2019

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

Sep 2020 - Present

Experience

Behavioural science practice intern

Ogilvy UK, London, UK

Research intern June – July 2018

UEA School of Psychology, Norwich, UK

The project focused on dyadic interactions in negotiation settings.

Senior ambassador Sep 2017 – June 2019

UEA Award, Norwich, UK

Delivered workshops and talks on professional development.

Advocacy Assistant Oct 2017 – June 2019

UEA Students' Union, Norwich, UK

Provided support to postgraduate students.

Cypriot National Guard

Platoon commander and director of my battalion's Administration office.

Publications

Efstratiou, A., & Marcinko, A. J. (2021). The leader oversight bias in justice and hypocrisy evaluations of organisational diversity practices. *Academy of Management Annual Proceedings*, 2021(1).

Awards & Honors

- Kurt Lewin prize as top performer in the 2019-2020 MSc Behavioural Science cohort at Durham University
- British Psychological Society Prize for Outstanding Undergraduate Degree
 Performance as top performer of the BSc Psychology cohort at UEA in all three years
 of study
- UEA School of Psychology prize for best dissertation project